<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neil Charlton |</title>
    <description>Making Stuff.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 21:09:17 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 21:09:17 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introducing Arduino</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For about 6 months now I’ve been following the progress of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arduino.cc/&quot;&gt;Ardunio&lt;/a&gt; which is a rapid prototying tool for your electronics ideas. It’s a sort of way of joining the software world  with the physical, tangible world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arduino.cc/&quot;&gt;Ardunio&lt;/a&gt; describes itself as “an open-source electronics platform based on flexible, easy-to-use hardware and software.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone who has been involved in software I’ve always had an interest in joining these two worlds. Will it be art, an invention or simply a thing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main attraction for me is the now easy availability of starter kits. Some clever people are producing packs available all over the web including Amazon featuring a plethora of different parts and projects. If it was really this easy I could not resist any longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not having a clue what I was doing (well I at least checked the &lt;a href=&quot;http://reddit.com/r/arduino&quot;&gt;Ardunio Subreddit&lt;/a&gt; for tips on starting out) I went ahead and ordered &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B009UKZV0A/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o00_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;this starter kit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/arduino-kit.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Uno&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comes with a decent easy to understand manual (RTFM!) which&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Walks you through the basics of Arduino and electronics in a hands-on way&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will help me build 15 projects using components that let me control the physical world through different kinds of sensors and actuators.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Includes over 100 components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally I can’t wait to get stuck in. Hopefully I’ll have something decent to show on here soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now here is a picture of the Arduino Microcontroller board at the heart of the pack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/arduino-uno-front.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Uno&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you had the chance to make anything cool with this yet? Even better how do I get the kids interested?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;

/**
*  RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
*  LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables*/

var disqus_config = function () {
this.page.url = PAGE_URL;  // Replace PAGE_URL with your page&#39;s canonical URL variable
this.page.identifier = &#39;Introducing Arduino&#39;; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page&#39;s unique identifier variable
};

(function() { // DON&#39;T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE
var d = document, s = d.createElement(&#39;script&#39;);
s.src = &#39;//neilcharlton-uk.disqus.com/embed.js&#39;;
s.setAttribute(&#39;data-timestamp&#39;, +new Date());
(d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
})();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 21:48:12 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/2016/introducing-arduino.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2016/introducing-arduino.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>hobby</category>
        
        <category>electronics</category>
        
        <category>arduino</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
